Sophie Treadwell papers, 1860s-1970 (bulk 1910-1960)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Sophie Treadwell papers, 1860s-1970 (bulk 1910-1960)
MS 318
Treadwell, Sophie, 1885-1970
Contains chiefly Personal Materials, Diaries, Correspondence, Scrap-books, Plays, Novels, and Photographs relating to her career as an American playwright, author, and journalist from the 1910s through the 1960s. Diaries include her travels to Europe and Moscow in the 1930s, and daily activities for selected years spanning 1942 to 1970. Noted correspondents include Louise and Walter Arensberg, Arthur Craven, Maynard Dixon, Helena Modjeska, Robert A. Parker, family and friends, colleagues, employers, and inter-view-ees, including Sarah Bernhardt and Francisco Villa. Scrapbooks document her private life; college years at University of California, 1901-1906; early acting, writing, and employment in California, New York, Europe, and Mexico, 1909-1932; and critical coverage of the productions of her dramatic works from 1918-1949.
10 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
On October 3, 1885, Sophie Anita Treadwell was born in Stockton, California, to Alfred B. Treadwell and Nettie Fairchild. From 1902 to 1906, she attended the University of California, Berkeley, where she participated in the theater arts. After graduation, she sought work in California as an actress and performer, and assisted Helena Modjeska in writing her Memoirs. Treadwell returned to San Francisco and began her newspaper career for the Bulletin. She married another journalist, William O. McGeehan, in 1910. She traveled to France as a war correspondent, and, by 1918, had moved to New York to work for the Tribune and other periodicals. She went to Mexico in the 1920s to cover the last days of Venustiano Carranza, and scooped other papers with her interview of Francisco Villa in 1921. In the 1930s, Treadwell traveled extensively. She circled the world in a steamer, and crossed the Atlantic several times to Europe while Machinal played in London, Moscow, and other venues. Lone Valley and Plumes in the Dust reached the New York stages. She published a novel, Lusita, and wrote another, Hope for a Harvest. In the next two decades, Treadwell continued to produce and revise her materials for publication, and for the emerging media of televi-sion. She retired to Tucson in 1965, and brought her final version of Women with Lilies to the stage of The University of Arizona. She died of a stroke on February 20, 1970.
William O'Connell McGeehan was born in San Francisco, California, to Hugh McGee-han and Theresa O'Connell in 1879. He attended Stanford University, and served in the Philippines during the Spanish American War. He worked as a journalist in San Francisco for the Evening Post, Examiner and Bulletin. Around 1914, he moved to New York and became a noted sports reporter for the New York Journal, the Herald Tribune and Herald. He traveled widely, hunted, wrote novels and short stories, and commuted between residences in Connecticut and New York. He died at Sea Island, Georgia, of a heart ailment on November 29, 1933.
Organization
This collection is organized into ten series
Series I: Personal materials, 1881-1969
Series II: Diaries and Trips, 1907-1970
Series III: Correspondence, 1884-1970
Series IV: Scrapbooks, 1901-1949
Series V: Plays, ca. 1905-1955
Series VI: Novels, 1939-1960s
Series VII: Supplemental Works, 1902-1967
Series VIII: Photographic materials, ca. 1860s-1960s
Series IX: Supplemental materials, ca. 1915-1950s
Series X: William O'Connell McGeehan Papers, 1900-1933
Scope and Content Note
Contains chiefly Personal Materials, Diaries, Correspondence, Scrap-books, Plays, Novels, and Photographs relating to her career as an American playwright, author, and journalist from the 1910s through the 1960s. Diaries include her travels to Europe and Moscow in the 1930s, and daily activities for selected years spanning 1942 to 1970. Noted correspondents include Louise and Walter Arensberg, Arthur Craven, Maynard Dixon, Helena Modjeska, Robert A. Parker, family and friends, colleagues, employers, and inter-view-ees, including Sarah Bernhardt and Francisco Villa. Scrapbooks document her private life; college years at University of California, 1901-1906; early acting, writing, and employment in California, New York, Europe, and Mexico, 1909-1932; and critical coverage of the productions of her dramatic works from 1918-1949. Works contain mainly her plays for stage, but also include television versions; novel drafts for Hope for a Harvest and The Story; and articles and features for newspapers and periodicals. Photographic materials consist chiefly of formal portraits by studio photographers; images of and by her while on trips or assignments in the United States, Europe and Mexico, including a interview with Francisco Villa in Canutillo; and casual moments with family members and friends. Also includes a small selection of Papers, 1909-1933, of husband William O'Connell McGeehan, 1879-1933, journalist and author.
Materials may be found in the following languages: Spanish, French, German, and Russian.
Related Material
Related material can be found in the following manuscript collection: Manuscript Collection 124, Sophie Treadwell Papers
Separated Material
The following material has been deaccessed: printed material: 3 feet of duplicates or supplemental materials.
The following books have been transferred to Special Collections: By Sophie Treadwell: Lusita, 1931; One Fierce Hour and Sweet, 1959. By William O. McGeehan: Trouble in the Balkans, 1931. Also: An Illustrated History of San Joaquin County, California, 1890; Blue and Gold,1906.
Craven, Arthur Scott, dd. 1917 -- Correspondence; Dixon, Maynard, 1875-1946 -- Archives; McGeehan, William O'Connell, 1879- -- Archives; Modjeska, Helena, 1840-1909 -- Correspondence; Parker, Robert Allerton -- Correspondence; Treadwell, Sophie, 1885-1970 -- Archives; Villa, Pancho, 1878-1923; Actors -- United States -- Correspondence; American drama -- Women authors; Authors, American -- 20th century -- Sources; Drama|y20th century -- Stories, plots, etc. -- Sources; Feminism and literature -- United States; Manuscripts, American; Theater -- United States -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; Women dramatists, American -- Sources; Women journalists -- United States -- Sources; Mexico -- History -- 1910-1946; Correspondence; Photographs; Scrapbooks
Container List
- Series I: Personal materials, 1881-1969
  - Biographical clippings. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Legal documents. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Passports. 1920-1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Autograph book of Nettie Fairchild. 1881-1894 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Address books. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bookplates and block. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Series II: Diaries and Trips, 1907-1970
  - Diary. 1907,1920,1931 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Diary, Moscow trip. May 20-June 6, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Diary. 1936, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Diary. November 1942-August 1943 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Diary. 1947, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Diary. 1949, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Diary. 1951, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Diary. December 1954-May 1955, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Diary. 1960, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Diary. 1962, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Diary. 1966, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Diary. 1969, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Trip to North Africa and Sicily. 1930 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Trip to Moscow. 1933 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Series III: Correspondence, 1884-1970
  - Unidentified correspondents: Al, Aline, Anna and Aerol (Beverly Hills), Beale, Betty (Conn.), Beulah (Hollywood), Delores C., Enelina, Evelyn, Helen, Lolly, Marguerite, Marty, Mary, Nil, Norman (Sag Harbor), Paul, Robert, Scoop (Mill Valley), Sue, Susan, Sylvia (Newtown), Terry, Walter. (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
  - Jacques. 1915-1916 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Llewelyn and Lulu. 1915-1930 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Agee, William F.; Ames, Winthrop; Antoine, Lore; and Arlson, H.L. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Arensberg, Louise and Walter. 1921-1922 (Box 4, Folder 6-7)
  - Barry, Griffin; Basquin, Anne; Bernhardt, Sarah; Bernstein, Oscar; Berrocal, Antonio; Boss, Suzanne; Bosworth, Hobart; Bozenta, Chalapowski (see Modjeska); Bozzano, Lino; and Breton, Judith. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Barney, Esther. 1906-1908, 1946-1969 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Bates, Dan and May. 1952-1953 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Brenan, Gerald. 1969 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - C?, Connie; Cesana, Luigi; Cook Travel Agency; and Crocker, Carlotta S. (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Caughlin, Jerry. 1945-1966 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Clark, Sonya T. 1951-1969 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Connell, Richard. 1930 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Cope, Harry. 1906-1908 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Courtney, William B. 1954-1955 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Craven, Arthur, includes Maintenant, 1:1 and 2:2. 1917, 1912-1913 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - De Sola, Francisco and Lenore; D'Herbois, Eleanor; Dramatic Workshop and Technical Institute; Duncan, Bessie; and Durant, Kenneth. (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Dixon, Maynard; includes poems, portrait and inscribed copy of Maynard Dixon: Painter of the West. 1916-1920, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Edwards, Dorothea. (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Fairchild, Anna; Farragut School; and Frey, Eugen. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Feibleman, Peter S. 1958-1959 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Gries, Lola. 1931-1955 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Gianolio, Piero; Gill, Becky and Helen Davis; Goeldner, Dolores; Gonet, Marjorie; Gonzalez, Gilberto; amd Gruner, Anne. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Gay, Gregory. 1952-1956 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Gregory, Jack. 1905-1909 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Gregory, Susan Myra, includes her poetry. 1906-1936 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Handgrave, Lisa; Harris, Harwell Hamilton; Hayden, Terese; Hayes, Marijane; High Class Amusement Enterprises (New York); Hill, Merle Miller Sherwood; Hillman, Richard Paul; Holmes Line Company; Howard, Mildred; and Hutton, Corrine. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Heunil ? (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Hodgkins, Helen. 1968 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Hofmann, Annie and family. 1935-1970 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Hood, Dorothy. 1944-1969 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Jones, Robert Edmond. 1937 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Kaufman, Agnes; Keen, Victor; King, Dorothy; Klausner, Bertha; Koiransky, H.; Krennwallner, Anna; and Krois, Adolf. (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Koiransky, Alesander. 1951-1952 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - La Pena, (?); Laszlo, Christa; Le Gallienne, Eva; Leginska, Ethel; Lloyd, Margaret; Loeb, Joseph P.; London, Jack; and Charmian Loubeque, Henry. (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Laning, Clair. 1949-1954 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Loza, Ignacio (Nacho). 1920-1970 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Machiz, Herbert; McClintic, Guthrie; McCoy, Helen Cooke; McLeish, Alexander; Meissner, Erma; Mexico [Officials and Agencies]; Meyer, Gert; Miller, Esther; Miller, Nellie; and Morris, Kate. (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - McGeehan, William O. 1909-1910, 1933 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - McReynolds, Isabel. 1905-1907 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Modjeska, Helena and Bozeta Chalapowski. 1908-1909 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Murchie, Kathe and Guy. 1958-1959 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - New York American; New York Herald Tribune; New York Public Library; Newberry, Bertha; and Norton (?), Louise. (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - O'Conner, Richard; O'Connor, Grover; Olds, Elizabeth and Larry; and Osborn, Anita. (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Parker, Florence Ann; Pegler, Westbrook; Petgen, Dorothea; and Pantages Theatre (San Francisco) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Parker, Robert Allerton and Jessie. 1921-1969 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Pelletier, Camille and Gaby. 1953-1969 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Peroche, Elisa. 1915-1916 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Ramos, Gerardo; Robbins, Helen; Rodin, Phyllis; Reed, John; and Rust (?), Ted (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Reinhardt, Martha. 1950-1954 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Rogoway, Marjorie and Alfred. 1955-1956 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Salisbury, Mrs.; San Francisco. Board of Education; San Francisco Bulletin; San Francisco Call; San Francisco Chronicle; Sanborn, Julia; Saus, H.F.; Schoenberner, Franz; Schotorino, T (?); Sherner, Jennifer; Skinner, Constance; Stanford, Alfred; and Steiner, Otto. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Sutherland, Luther. 1915-1919, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Theatre Guild, Inc. (New York), and Tucson Daily Citizen. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Treadwell, Alfred B. 1884-1912 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Treadwell, Nettie. 1905-1907 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - U-V; U.S.S.R. Society of Cultural Relations; Vogt (?), Ursula; Vas-Waner, Maria; and Von Neumayer, Charles. (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Villa, Francisco. 1921 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Wells, Evelyn; Westerwelt-Folina, Mary Beth; Wheeler, Howard; Whittaker, J.H.E.; Wilder, Mrs.; Williams, Irene and Irma; Wilson, Leon; and Zuber, Mrs. Carl H. (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Series IV: Scrapbooks, 1901-1949
  - Scrapbook 1 covers Treadwell's college years at University of California at Berkeley. Memorabilia includes dance cards, invita-tions, pro-grams, letters, photo-graphs, news clippings, grades, and songs, poems, speeches and plays written by the author. 1901-1906 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook 2 is entitled "Vagabondage," and spans her adventures as a teacher at Yankee Jim's, as a govern-ess in Modoc County, California, and also her early days of theater and writing in Los Angeles and San Francisco. Includes photo-graphs, letters, theater playbills, play scripts, and newspaper articles by Treadwell, including her first story published in the San Fran-cisco Bulletin in 1908. One article covers her theater debut, under the name of Willia Williams, at the Fischer Theater, San Francisco, in 1907. 1906-1909 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook 3 includes, "Sophie Treadwell, Her Book," it contains photographs, poems, letters, and news arti-cles. It includes her early years with W.O. McGeehan, their wedding announcement in 1910, and typed and handwritten poems apparently written by Treadwell and McGeehan. A play program from The Toad, 1912, in which Treadwell performed in Carmel; various newspaper articles that she wrote for the Bulletin in 1914, and two letters from Jack London and his wife are also present. 1909-1914 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook 4 contains her first serial for the Bulletin, "An Outcast at the Christian Door." It con-sists of seventeen installments; the last one, the 18th, appears to be missing. There are also editorials and responses in reaction to the publication of this serial. 1914 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook 8 has approximately twenty articles from the New York American about the Mohr murder trial of 1916 that Treadwell covered for the paper. Also contains three other unrelated articles she wrote for this paper. 1916 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook 5 is entirely devoted to another serial, "How I got my husband and how I lost him: the story of Jean Traig," published in the Bulletin. It consists of fifty-two install-ments, original photographs that were used in the articles, and press accounts of Jean Traig starring in a play that Treadwell subsequently wrote. 1914-1915 (Box 9)
  - Scrapbook 6 covers the year 1915 when Treadwell was sent to France in April as a war correspondent for the Bulletin, and also for Harper's Weekly. The items include passports, French documents, letters of introduction, postcards, maps, letters, souvenirs and photographs. There are carbon copies of the six articles she sent to the Bulletin in letter format, and a letter from her critical editor unhappy with her writing so far. There is a telegram from Sarah Bernhardt and a typed interview with her, entitled "Madame Walks Again". 1915 (Box 10)
  - Scrapbook 7 documents when Treadwell went to Mexico as a correspondent from the New York Tribune in 1920 to cover the murder of the Mexican president, Don Venustiano Carranza. There are letters, newspaper articles (some in Spanish) and photographs including some of Francisco "Pancho" Villa. Includes her exclusive interview with Villa at his ranch, Canutillo, in Durango, Mexico. In 1924, Treadwell wrote a nine-part series on Mexico titled "The Mirage of Mexico" for the Tribune, and this series is included here. Articles concerning her novel about Mexico, Lusita, published in 1931, are also here. 1920-1932 (Box 11)
  - Scrapbook 9 encompasses her stage productions, including announcements, programs and reviews from a variety of eastern newspapers for Claws (1918, which she acted in), Gringo (1922, her first Broadway production that she wrote), Lonely Lee (1923, with Helen Hayes), O Nightingale (1925), Ladies Leave (1929), The Island (1929), Better to Marry, Bound and Wild Honey (all in 1927), Lone Valley (1932), and Plumes in the Dust (1936). Also present are clippings from 1924 when Treadwell sued John Barrymore over a play about Edgar Allen Poe that she believed was based on a version that she had written and given to Barrymore a few years earlier. 1918-1936 (Box 12)
  - Scrapbook 10 concerns the production of Machinal, based on the Ruth Snyder and Judd Grey murder case in 1928. It was staged by Arthur Hopkins with settings by Robert Edmund Jones, and began at the Plymouth theater starring Zita Johann, and an unknown actor named Clark Gable. There are reviews of it in London in 1931 under the title The Life Machine. It was also produced as Mrs. Jones in Moscow in 1934, and there are Russian news clippings. 1928-1934 (Box 13)
  - Scrapbook 11 consists of articles and reviews about her Broadway production of Hope for a Harvest. The play was staged at a number of Eastern cities and the reviews are from a variety of newspapers. 1941 (Box 14)
  - Scrapbook 12 contains clippings and photographs of William O. McGeehan. There are approximately twenty editorials from his tenure with the Evening Post in San Francis-co in 1910. As sports editor at the New York Herald Tribune in 1924, some of his "Down the Line" columns are present. McGeehan also covered the Scopes trial in Dayton, Tennessee, for the Tribune in 1927, and there are a few of these articles. From 1930-1933 he wrote columns of his travels throughout Africa and Europe, and of his attendance at the 1932 Olympic Games at Lake Placid, New York. McGeehan died in 1933 in Georgia, and there are articles and tributes to him from newspapers in America and England. About one-quarter of this scrapbook consists of photographs of McGeehan and friends during World War I in uniform, and while hunting, fishing, and camping. Some images include the boxer Gene Tunney. 1910-1949 (Box 15)
- Series V: Plays, ca. 1905-1955
  - To Him Who Waits, carbon, some revisions. 1917-1918 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - La Cachucha. 1918 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Eye of the Beholder, original. 1919 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Tom, Dick and Harriet. 1905 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Le Grand Prix, original. ca. 1906-1907 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Wintering it at Yankee Jim's, original. 1907-1908 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - The Settlement, original. 1911 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Constance Darrow. 1911 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Claws, original. 1918 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Madam Bluff, original. 1918 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - The Answer. 1918 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - The Limelight. 1919 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Poe, (3 acts, 6 scenes), original. 1920 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Rights (second version), original. 1921 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - By Mrs. Beaton. 1921 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Love and Principle, original. 1941 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Gringo, original. 1922 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - O Nightingale, original. 1923 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Many Mansions. 1925 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - You Can't have Everything (first version), original. 1925 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Lone Valley (10th version), original. 1926 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Machinal, (1st version? 8 episodes) original. 1928 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Machinal, (N.Y. / London / Moscow version: 9 episodes). 1928 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Machinal, (3 acts, 9 scenes: Little Theatre version). 1928 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Machinal, (acting version: 9 episodes). 1928 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Ladies Leave, original. 1929 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - The Island, original (Rialto copy). 1930 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - A Million Dollar Gate, (final version). 1930 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Andrew Wells' Lady, (Rialto copy). 1931 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - The Promised Land, (Rialto copy) original. 1933 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Three, (version 1a) original. 1936 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Three, (2nd version) original. 1936 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Hope for a Harvest, (A.H. version) original. 1938 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Hope for a Harvest, (French's Library Edition). 1942 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Highway, (2 acts) original. 1942 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - The Last Border, (3rd version: mimeograph). 1944 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Don't Leave Me, (2 acts). 1940s (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Woman with Lilies, (2 acts). 1948 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - The Gorgeous Innocent, (television play) carbon. 1950s (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Judgement in the Morning, (2 acts 4 scenes) carbon. 1952 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Judgement in the Morning, (3 acts: MCA version). 1952 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - A String of Pearls, (MCA version). 1953 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - The Siren, carbon. 1953 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Love for a Criminal, (2 acts 4 scenes) original. 1954 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - In Loving Lost, original. 1955 (Box 19, Folder 7)
- Series VI: Novels, 1939-1960s
  - Hope for the Harvest. 1939-1940 (Box 19, Folder 8-10)
  - The Story, (1st version). 1960s (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - The Story, (2nd version). 1960s (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - The Great Name Story, (3rd version). 1960s (Box 20, Folder 3)
- Series VII: Supplemental Works, 1902-1967
  - College papers and stories. 1902-1906 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - "A break in the levee." 1906 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - "Amateur night." 1907 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - "The story of muh life." 1908 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - "Madame Walks Again," (Sarah Bernhardt interview). 1915 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - "The Holy City." (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper articles. ca. 1909-1926 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Fragments. (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Printed materials from Plays. 1918-1967 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Reviews of Treadwell works. 1904-1967 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Index cards to play "Lucky Stars." (Box 20, Folder 14)
- Series VIII: Photographic materials, ca. 1860s-1960s
  - Infant, young girl. 1886-1905 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Young woman. 1905-1917 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Actress in college and Carmel plays. 1904, 1912 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - At Stockton, Old Trees Ranch. 1910s (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - At Yankee Jim's, California. 1911-1917 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Auto trip across United States with Esther. 1917 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Mexico. ca. 1920 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Paris, New York. ca. 1917-1929 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - With Louise Arensberg, Henri-Pierre Roché, Robert A. Parker. 1918 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Portraits, by Bachrach, 1925. 1925 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Esther's Ranch, Los Gatos, California, "Mom's little house." ca. 1929 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - New York, Mexico, and other places. 1930s-1960s (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Europe. 1930s-1960s (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Residences and pet. (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - William O. McGeehan. 1910s-1933 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Fishing, hunting, etc., includes Gene Tunney. 1920s-1930s (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Burial site (William O. McGeehan). 1933 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Anna Fairchild (grandmother). (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - William and Anna Fairchild, (2 daguerreotypes). 1860s (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Nettie Fairchild (mother; includes 1 tintype). 1870s (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Alfred B. Treadwell (father). (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Fairchilds: Hershel (uncle), Josephine Swain (aunt). (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - William Treadwell (son). 1960s (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Harry Cope, Jack London. (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Ignacio and Nidia Loza. (Box 22, Folder 8)